Finding Aid for the Lawrence Morton Papers LSC.1522
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Research Material
  - Stravinsky, Books By or About
    - Casella, Alfredo--Strawinski: Nuove editione con un capitolo di aggiornamento di Guglielmo Bar Blan., 1951. (Box 22)
      Brescia: La Scuola Editrice.
    - Lesure, Francois--Stravinsky: Etudes et temoignages. Presentes et reunis par Francois Lesure., 1982. (Box 22)
      Paris: Editions Jean-Claude Lattes.
    - Libman, Lillian--And music at the close: Stravinsky's last years, a personal memoir., 1972. (Box 23)
      Inscribed To Lawrence who always sought the truth--Love--Lillian, August 17, 1972.
    - Mila, Massimo--Igor Strawinsky: Carriera d'un libertino (The rake's progress), Guidomusicale., 1952. (Box 23)
      n.p.: Istituto D'Alto Cultura.
    - Myers, Rollo H.--Introduction to the music of Stravinsky., 1950. (Box 23)
      London: Dennis Dobson Limited.
    - Jers, Norbert--Igor Strawinsky's spate Zwolfton Werke (1958-1966)., 1976. (Box 23)
      Regensburg: Gustave Bosse Verlag.
    - Joseph, Charles M.--Stravinsky and the piano., 1983. (Box 23)
      Ann Arbor, Michigan: UMI Research Press.
    - Lourie, Arthur--Profanation et sanctification du temps: Journal musical Saint Petersbourg - Paris - New York, 1910-1960., 1966. (Box 23)
      Paris: Desclee de Brouwer.
    - Lindlar, Heinrich--Igor Strawinsky: Sadraler gesang, Geist und Form der Christ-kutischen Kompositionen., 1957. (Box 23)
    - Lederman, Minna (ed.)--Stravinsky in the theater., 1949. (Box 23)
      With an introduction by Minna Lederman.
      New York: Pellegrini & Cudahy.
    - Lederman, Minna (ed.)--Stravinsky in the theatre., 1975. (Box 23)
    - Kirchmeyer, Helmut--Igor Strawinsky, Zeitgeschichte im Personlichskeitsbild: Grundlagen und Voraussetzungen zur modernen Konstruktionstechnik., 1958. (Box 23)
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Igor Strawinsky, herausgegeben von Heinz-Klaus Metzger und Rainer Riehn., 1984. (Box 23)
      Musik-Konzepte, Heft 34/35, n.p.: n.p.
    - Kirchmeyer, Helmut--Strawinskys russische Ballette, Der Feuervogel, Petrouschka, Le Sacre du Printemps, 1974. (Box 23)
      Stuttgart: Phillipp Reclam Jun.
    - Lang, Paul Henry (ed.)--Stravinsky: A new appraisal of his work, with a complete list of works., 1963. (Box 23)
      Contributors include Lang, E.T. Cone, Wilfred Mellers, Lawrence Morton, Robert V. Nelson, Boris Schwarz and Carroll D. Wade.
    - Lederman, Minna (ed.)--Stravinsky in the theater: A symposium prepared by Minna Lederman., 1947. (Box 23)
      Dance Index, vol.VI (10-12) New York.
    - Malipiero, G.F.--Strawinsky., 1945. (Box 23)
      Venezia: Cavallino.
    - Horgan, Paul--Encounters with Stravinsky: A personal record., 1972. (Box 24)
      New York: Farrar Straus and Giroux.
    - Siohan, Robert--Stravinsky., 1965. (Box 24)
      Translated by Eric Walter White.
      London: Boyars Limited.
    - Keller, Hans and Milein Cosman--Stravinsky seen and heard., 1982. (Box 24)
      n.p.: Toccata Press.
      English version of Stravinsky dirigiert by Cosman & Keller in Box 20.
    - White, Eric Walter, and Jeremy Noble--Igor Stravinsky. In Modern Masters: Bartok, Stravinsky, Hindemith., 1984. (Box 24)
      New York and London: W.W. Norton & Company.
    - Herzfeld, Friedrich--Igor Strawinsky., 1961. (Box 24)
      Berlin: Rembrandt Verlag.
    - Siohan, Robert--Stravinsky., 1970. (Box 24)
      New York: Grossman Publishers.
    - Boucourechliev, Andre, Olivier Merlin, Michel Philippot, Claude Rostand, Claude Samuel, Henri Sauguet, Marcel Schneider, and Harry Halbreich--Stravinsky: Collection genies et realites., 1968. (Box 24)
      France: Hachette.
    - Handschin, Jacques--Igor Stravinsky., 1933. (Box 24)
      Zurich und Leipzig: Kommissionsverlag von Hug & Company.
    - Hirsbrunner, Theo--Igor Strawinsky in Paris., 1982. (Box 24)
      Berlin: Laaber-Verlag.
    - Strobel, Heinrich--Stravinsky: Classic humanist., 1955. (Box 24)
      Translated from the German by Hans Rosenwald.
      New York: Merlin Press.
    - Tansman, Alexandre--Igor Stravinsky, ouvrage enrichi de 17 hors-texte., 1948. (Box 25)
      Paris: Amiot-Dumont.
    - Strobel, Heinrich--Igor Strawinsky., 1956. (Box 25)
      Zurich: Atlantis Verlag.
    - Strawinsky, Theodore--The message of Igor Stravinsky., 1953. (Box 25)
      Translated from the original French text by Robert Craft and Andre Marion.
      London: Boosey & Hawkes, Limited.
    - Strawinsky, Theodore--Igor Strawinsky: Mensch und Kunstler (Le Message d'Igor Strawinsky). (Box 25)
      Mainz: B. Schott's Sohne.
    - Strawinsky, Theodore--Le Message d'Igor Strawinsky (edition definitive), precede d'une lettre d'Igor Strawinsky., 1980. (Box 25)
      Lausanne: Editions de l'Aire.
    - Tansman, Alexandre--Igor Stravinsky: The man and his music., 1949. (Box 25)
      Translated by Therese and Charles Bleefeld.
      New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons.
    - Stuckenschmidt, Hans Heinz--Strawinsky und sein Jahrhundert., 1957. (Box 25)
      Berlin: Akademie Der Kunst.
    - Passaquet, Raphael--Igor Stravinsky: Petroushka., 1959. (Box 26)
      Paris: Peuple et Culture.
    - Ramuz, C.F.--Souvenirs sur Igor Strawinsky., 1952. (Box 26)
      Mermod: n.p.
    - Schaeffner, Andre--Strawinsky., 1938. (Box 26)
      Paris: Les Editions Rieder.
    - Souvtchinsky, Pierre--Stravinsky: Aupres et au loin., 1982. (Box 26)
      n.p.: J. Clattes.
      Inserted in this pamphlet is a 6pp. summary by L.M. of the 14 points in Souvchinsky's work.
    - Ramuz, C.F.--Erinnerungen an Igor Strawinsky., n.d. (Box 26)
      Ubertragen von Leonharda Gescher.
      Berlin und Frankfurt: Suhrkamp Verlag.
    - Lindlar, Heinrich--Lubbes Strawinsky Lexikon., 1982. (Box 26)
      n.p.: Gustave Lubbe Verlag.
    - Sopena, Federico--Strawinsky: Vida, obro y estilo., 1956. (Box 26)
      Madrid: Sociedad de Estudios Y Publicaciones.
    - Ramuz, C.F.--Souvenirs sur Igor Strawinsky., 1978. (Box 26)
      Avant-propos de Pierre-Paul Clement.
      Lausanne: Foundation C.F. Ramuz, Editions de L'Aire.
    - Stoveick, Dietrich--Zwei Ballete: Der Feuervogel von Igor Strawinsky un Hamlet von Boris Blacher., 1969. (Box 26)
      Berlin-Lichterfeld: Robert Lienau.
    - Strawinsky, Theodore--Le Message D'Igor Strawinsky., 1948. (Box 26)
      Lausanne: Librarie F. Fouge.
    - Scharchuch, Horst--Analyse zu Igor Strawinsky's Sacre du Printemps., 1960. (Box 26)
      Regensburg: Gustav Bosse Verlag.
    - Schloezer, Boris de--Igor Stravinsky., 1929.; In wrappers. Clothbound edition. (Box 26)
      Paris: Editions Claude Aveline.
      Inserted in the dustjacket is a newspaper review by Carl Dahlhous of Volker Sherliess, Stravinsky un seine Zeit. (Laaber: Laaber Verlag, 1983).
    - Siohan, Robert--Igor Strawinsky in Selbstzeugnissen und Bilddokumenten., 1959. (Box 26)
      Dargestellt von Robert Siohan. Rowohlts Monographien, herausgegeben von Kurt Kusenburg.
      Paris: Rowohlt, mit Genehmigung des Verlages Editions du Seuil.
    - Siohan, Robert--Stravinsky., 1959. (Box 26)
      n.p.: Editions du Seuil.
    - Lesure, Francoise--Igor Stravinsky Le Sacre du Printemps: Dossier de Presse (Press-Book)., 1980. (Box 28)
      Geneve: Editions Minkoff.
    - Schouvaloff, Alexander, and Victor Borovsky--Stravinsky on stage., 1982. (Box 29)
      London: Stainer Bell.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Themes and conclusions., 1982. (Box 29)
    - Stravinsky, Vera, and Robert Craft--Stravinsky in pictures and documents., 1978. (Box 29)
    - Avedon, Richard--Portraits., 1976. (Box 30)
      New York: Farrar, Straus and Giroux.
    - Stravinsky, Theodore--Catherine & Igor Stravinsky: A family album., 1973. (Box 31)
    - Newman, Arnold--Bravo Stravinsky., 1967. (Box 31)
      Text by Robert Craft. Foreword by Frances Steegmuller.
      Cleveland: The World Wide Publishing Company.
    - Tomek, Otto, herausgegeben--Igor Strawinsky, eine sonderiehe des Westdeutschen Rundfunks zum 80. Geburtstag., 1963. (Box 35)
      Koln: Westdeutscher Rundfunk.
    - Vlad, Roman--Stravinsky., 1971. (Box 35)
      Translated from the Italian by Frederick and Ann Fuller, second edition.
      London: Oxford University Press.
    - Vechten, Carl Van--Music after the great war., 1915. (Box 36)
      New York: G. Schirmer.
      Includes Igor Strawinsky: a new composer pp.85-117.
    - Trapp, Michael--Studien zu Strawinsky's Geshichten vom Soldaten (1918): Zur Idee und Wirkungdes Musiktheaters der 1920 er Jahre., 1978. (Box 36)
      Kolner Beitrage zur Musikforschung, ed. by Heinrich Huschen. vol.96.
    - Vlad, Roman--Strawinsky., 1958. (Box 36)
      Torino: Guilio Einaudi.
    - White, Eric Walter--Stravinsky: The composer and his works., 1979. (Box 36)
      Second edition.
      Berkeley and Los Angeles: The University of California Press--Worcester & London: The Trinity Press.
    - White, Eric Walter--Stravinsky: The composer and his works., 1966. (Box 36)
      Berkeley: University of California Press--London: Faber and Faber.
    - Toorn, Pieter C. Van den--The music of Igor Stravinsky., 1983. (Box 36)
      Composers of the Twentieth Century, Allen Forte, general editor.
    - Tierney, Neil--The unknown country: A life of Igor Stravinsky., 1977. (Box 37)
      London: Robert Hale Limited.
    - Tintori, Giampiero--Igor Stravinsky., 1966.; Two copies; one in wrappers. (Box 37)
      Traduit de l'Italien par Guillemette de Beauville.
      Paris: Editions du Sud.
    - White, Eric Walter--Stravinsky., [1949]. (Box 37)
      Ubertragung Gottfried Von Einem.
      Hamburg: Claassen Verlag.
    - White, Eric Walter--Stravinsky: A critical survey., 1947. (Box 37)
      London: John Lehman.
    - Smirnov, V.--Tvorcheskoe formirovanie I.F. Stravinskogo., 1970. (Box 38)
      Leningrad: Muzyka.
    - Druskin, M.--Igor Stravinskii: lichnost', tvorchestvo, vzgliady., 1974. (Box 38)
      Leningrad: Sovetskii kompozitor.
    - Kovshar, I.F.--Igor Stravinskii: Rannee tvorchestvo., 1969. (Box 38)
      Baku: Elm.
    - Iarustovskii, B.--Igor Stravinskii: Kratki ocherk zhizni i tvorchestva., 1963. (Box 38)
      Moskva: Soverskii kompozitor.
    - Vershinina, I.I.A.--Rannye balety Stravinskogo: Zhar-ptitsa, Petrushka, Vesnasviashchennaia., 1967. (Box 38)
      Moskva: Nauka.
    - Asaf'ev, B.--Kniga o Stravinskom., 1977. (Box 38)
      Leningrad, Muzyka.
    - Glebov, Igor--Kniga o Stravinskom., 1929. (Box 38)
      Leningrad: Triton.
    - Stravinsky, Igor and Robert Craft--Samtaler med Stravinsky., 1962. (Box 38)
      Til norsk ved Pauline Hall.
      Oslo: J.W. Cappelens Forlag.
    - Korev, I.U.--Russkaia professional'naia muzyka do 1917 goda., 1958. (Box 38)
      Moskva: Muzgiz.
    - Stravinskaia, E.I.U.--O.I.F. Stravinskom i ego blizkikh., 1978. (Box 38)
    - Stravinskii, Igor--Dialogi: Vospominaniia, razmyshleniia, kommentarii., 1971. (Box 38)
    - Ruppel, K.H. (ed.)--Music Viva 217 Abbildungen., 1959. (Box 39)
      Munchen: Nymphenburger Verlagshandlung.
    - Jarustowski, Boris--Igor Strawinsky., 1966, originalausgabe von 1937. (Box 39)
      Aus dem Russischen ubertragen von Urte Hartwig.
      Berlin: Henschelverlag.
    - Young, Percy M.--Stravinsky., 1969, reprinted 1970. (Box 39)
      Masters of Music Series. New York: Cornerstone Library.
    - Handschin, Jacques--Igor Strawinski., 1933. (Box 39)
      Zurich: Kommissionsverlag von Hug & Company.
    - White, Eric Walter--Stravinsky's sacrifice to Apollo., 1930. (Box 39)
      London: The Hogarth Press.
    - Armitage, Merle (ed.)--Igor Stravinsky: Articles and critiques., 1936. (Box 70)
      E. Goosens, H. Boys, O.Downes, M. Armitage, E. Vuillermoz, L. Danz, J. Rodriquez, M. Komroff, J. Cocteau, E. Satie, & an abridged analyses by Boris de Schloezer.
      Inscribed on the half title page to Douglas Fairbanks junior in sympathetic remembrance from Igor Strawinsky Hollywood March 37.
    - Craft, Robert--A Stravinsky scrapbook 1940-1971., 1983. (Box 90)
      Illustrations chosen by Patricia Schwark.
      Cambridgeshire: Thames and Hudson, Limited.
      Inscribed on frontispiece To L.M. from R.C. etc. March/83.
    - Craft, Robert, Vera Stravinsky, and Rita McCaffrey--Igor and Vera Stravinsky: A photograph album 1921 to 1971., 1982. (Box 90)
      Text from Stravinsky's interviews 1912-1963.
      n.p.: Thames and Hudson.
  - Stravinsky, Books Relating to or Referring to
    - Basart, Ann P--Perspectives of New Music: An index, 1962-1982. (Box 13)
      Perspectives of New Music.
    - Lederman, Minna--The life and death of a small magazine (Modern Music, 1924-1946)., 1983. (Box 14)
      Brooklyn: Institute for Studies in American Music, Brooklyn College of the City University of New York.
    - Shirley, Wayne D.--Modern Music: An analytic index., 1976. (Box 17)
      Edited by William and Carol Lichtenwanger.
      New York: AMS Press.
      Note on inside cover in L.M.'s hand I have vol.5 no.2, vol.7 no.2-3, vol.8 no.4, vol.9 no.1, vol.10 no.4, vol.11 no.2, vol.12 no.2-3, vol.13 to the end.
    - Nabokov, Nicolas--Old friends and new music., 1951. (Box 22)
      Boston: Little Brown and Company.
    - Gorodetskii, Sergei--Perun: Stikhotvoreniia liricheskiia i liroepicheskiia., 1907. (Box 30)
      Oblozhka (frontispis) raboty L.S. Baksta.
      S. Peterburg: Ory.
      Photocopy of Cyrillic publication--Author and title have been transliterated in pencil on the title page.
    - Gorodetskii, Sergei--IAr: Stikhi liricheskie i liro-epicheskie., 1907. (Box 30)
    - Korotkina, Liudmila--Nicholas Roerich., 1976. (Box 30)
      Leningrad: Aurora Art Publishers.
    - Kniazeva, V.P.--N. Rerikh., 1968. (Box 31)
      Moskva: Iskusstvo.
    - Noblitt, Thomas L. (ed.)--Index to Tempo January 1939-June 1972, prepared under the direction of and edited by Thomas L. Noblitt., 1977. (Box 35)
      n.p.: KTO Press.
    - Goldner, Nancy--The Stravinsky Festival of the New York City Ballet., 1973. (Box 35)
      With photographs by Martha Swope and others.
      New York: The Eakins Press.
    - Ziloti, Aleksandr Il'ich--Aleksandr Il'ich Ziloti, 1863-1945: Vospominaniia i pis'ma., 1963. (Box 38)
      Leningrad: Gos. muzykal'noe izd-vo.
    - No author--Stravinskii, F. Stat'i, pis'ma, vospominaniia., 1972. (Box 38)
    - Peyser, Joan--The new music: The sense behind the sound., 1971. (Box 55)
      With an introduction by Jacques Barzun.
      New York: Dell Publishing Company, Incorporated.
      Two bookmarks refer two passages on Stravinsky, where L.M. has made comments in red pencil.
    - Afanas'ev, Aleksandr--Russian fairy tales., 1973. (Box 55)
      Translated by Alexander Alexeieff from the collections of Aleksandr Afanas'ev. Folkloristic commentary by Roman Jakobson.
      New York: Pantheon Books, A division of Random House.
      L.M. has made pencil marks in the table of contents near stories that relate to Renard.
    - Kerman, Joseph--Opera as drama., 1956. (Box 55)
    - Osborne, Charles--W.H. Auden: The life of a poet., 1979. (Box 55)
      New York and London: Harcourt Brace Javanovich, Incorporated.
    - Thompson, Kenneth--St. Martin's dictionary of twentieth-century composers (1911-1971)., 1973. (Box 55)
      New York: St. Martin's Press, Incorporated.
    - Bedford, Sybille--Aldous Huxley: A biography., 1974. (Box 55)
      New York: Alfred A. Knopf, Incorporated and Harper & Row, Publishers, Incorporated.
      Insert after free end paper, clipping of a review by George Steiner (The New Yorker, February 17, 1975. pp.103-106.
    - Rosenfeld, Paul--Musical portraits: Interpretations of twenty modern composers., 1920. (Box 56)
      New York: Harcourt, Brace and Howe, Incorporated.
    - Cocteau, Jean--Le Rappel a l'ordre: Le Coq et l'arlequin, carte blanche, visites a Maurice Barres, Le secret professionel, D'un ordre considere comme une anarchie, Autour de Thomas l'imposteur, Picasso., 1948. (Box 56)
      Paris: Editions Stock.
    - Souvtchinsky, Pierre (ed.)--Musique Russe (Tome II)., 1953. (Box 56)
      Par Boris de Schloezer, Antoine Golea, Francis Poulenc, Charles Koechlin, Leon Algazi, Constantin Brailoiu et Vladimir Fedorov
      Biblioteque Internationale de Musicologie. Paris: Presses Universitaires de France.
    - Baedeker, K--Russland: Handbuch fur reisende, mit 14 karten, 18 planen un 4 grundressen. Vierte auflage., 1897. (Box 56)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul--Musical Chronicle (1917-1923). (Box 56)
      New York: Harcourt, Brace and Company, Incorporated.
    - Souvtchinsky, Pierre (ed.)--Musique Russe (Tome premier)., 1953.; 2 copies. (Box 56)
      Par Pierre Souvtchinsky, Vladimir Fedorov, Gisele Brelet, Henry Barraud, Andre Schaeffner, Yves Baudrier, Pierre Boulez.
      Bibliotheque Internationale de Musicologie. Paris: Presses Universitaires de France.
      Inscribed on the half-title A mes ami Lawrence Morton [] P. Souvtchinsky Paris, [].
    - Michel, Georges-Michel--Gens de theatre: Que j'ai connus 1900-1940., n.d. (Box 56)
      New York: Brentano's.
    - Leonard, Richard Anthony--A history of Russian music, with 17 illustrations., 1957. (Box 57)
      New York: The Macmillan Company.
      Frontispiece (title page) is a photograph of Stravinsky.
    - Debussy, Claude--Lettres a deux amis: Soixante-dix-huit lettres inedites a Robert Godey et G. Jean-Aubry., 1942. (Box 57)
      Paris: Librairie Jose Corti.
    - Cortot, Alfred--La Musique francaise de piano (Troisieme serie)., 1948. (Box 57)
      Les Six et le piano, Albert Roussel, Igor Strawinsky, Erik Satie, Gabriel Pierne, Gustave Samazeuilh.
      Paris: Presses Universitaires de France.
    - Godowsky, DagMarch--First person plural: The lives of DagMarch Godowsky., 1958. (Box 57)
      New York: The Viking Press, Incorporated.
    - Wasserstrom, William (ed.)--A dial miscellany., 1963. (Box 57)
      Syracuse, New York: Syracuse University Press.
      Contains Cocteau's Cock and Harlequin, translated by Rollo H. Myers.
    - Adorno, Theodor W.--Philosophy of modern music., 1973. (Box 57)
      Translated by Anne G. Mitchell and Wesley V. Blomster.
      New York: The Seabury Press.
    - Acosta, Mercedes de--Here lies the heart., 1960. (Box 57)
      New York: Arno Press.
    - Armitage, Merle--Accent on life., 1965. (Box 57)
      Forward by John Charles Thomas.
      Ames: The Iowa State University Press.
      Insert p.190--An interview with the author (clipping from the Citizen News {Los Angeles) Thursday, January 6, 1965).
    - Calvocoressi, M.D., and Gerald Abraham--Masters of Russian music., 1944. (Box 57)
      New York: Tudor Publishing Company.
    - Guerney, Bernard Guilbert (ed.)--A treasury of Russian literature. Being a comprehensive selection of many of the best things by numerous authors in practically every field of the rich literature of Russia from its beginnings to the present., 1945. (Box 58)
      In English, [with] all of the accepted favorites newly translated or their current translations thoroughly revised.
      Philadelphia: The Blakiston Company.
    - Afanasjev, Aleksandr Nikolaevic--Antiche fiabe russe., 1953. (Box 58)
      Traduzione de Gigliola Venturi. Prefazione di Franco Venturi.
      Torino: Giulio Einaudi editore.
      Boxed Italian edition.
    - Ansermet, Ernest--Les fondements d la musique dans la conscience humaine: Notes., 1961. (Box 58)
      Neuchatel: Editions de la Baconniere.
      Errata list inserted after copyright page.
    - Mirsky, D.S.--A history of Russian literature, comprising a history of Russian literature and contemporary Russian literature., 1958. (Box 58)
      Edited and abridged by Francis J. Whitfield.
      New York: Alfred A. Knopf, Incorporated.
    - Ansermet, Ernest--Les fondements de la musique dans la conscience humaine., 1961. (Box 58)
      Errata list and circular insert above half title. Dust jacket set to p.480 Stravinsky with pencil notes.
    - Asaf'ev, B.V. (Igor Glebov)--Russian music, from the beginning of the nineteenth century (1930)., 1953. (Box 58)
      Translated from the Russian by Alfred J. Swan.
      Ann Arbor, Michigan: Edwards Brothers, Incorporated.
      Translation of Russkaya muzyka ot nachala XIX stoletiya by B.V. Asaf'ev (Igor Glebov), published by the 'Academia' Press, Moscow-Leningrad, U.S.S.R., 1930. Pencil references on free end paper (verso).
    - Pougin, Arthur--Essai historique sur la musique en russie., 1904. (Box 58)
      Paris: Librairie Fischbacher.
    - Grigoriev, S.L.--The Diaghilev Ballet (1909-1929)., 1953. (Box 59)
      Translated and edited by Vera Bowen.
      London: Constable and Company Limited.
      In L.M.'s hand on paste-down end paper: Errors: 185, 243, 271.
    - Sokolova, Lydia--Dancing for Diaghilev: The memoirs of Lydia Sokolova., 1960. (Box 59)
      Edited by Richard Buckle.
      London: John Murray (Publishers) Limited.
    - Haskell, Arnold, in collaboration with Walter Nouvel--Diaghileff: His artistic and private life., 1947. (Box 59)
      Inscribed on paste-down end paper inverted: Dear Lawrence, When I saw this on the second-hand shelf I thought maybe I should pick it up for you; and when I saw how the thing was bound I knew you had to have it-Joe Kerman London July 4, 1960.
    - Lifar, Serge--Serge de Diaghilev: Sa vie, son oeuvre, sa legende., 1954. (Box 59)
      Preface par Jean-Louis Vaudoyer de l'Academie francaise.
      Pencil page references on free end paper (Verso) Brussel on Oiseau, 207 Petroushka--origin of title 225.
    - Georges-Michel, Michel--Ballets russes: Histoire anecdotique suivie d'un appendice et du Poeme de Sheherazade., 1923. (Box 59)
      Paris: Editions du Monde Nouveau.
    - Lauze, F. de (1623)--Apologie de la danse: A treatise of instruction in dancing and deportment given in the original French with a translation, introduction and notes by Joan Wildeblood., 1952. (Box 59)
      Music transcribed by Eduardo M. Torner.
      London: Frederick Muller Limited.
    - Spencer, Charles, Philip Dyer, and Martin Battersby--The world of Serge Diaghilev., 1979. (Box 59)
      Middlesex: Penguin Books Limited.
    - Haskell, Arnold L., and Mary Clarke--The ballet annual 1963: A record and year book of the ballet. Seventeenth issue., 1962. (Box 59)
      London: Adan and Charles Black.
    - Massine, Leonide--My life in ballet., 1968. (Box 59)
      Edited by Phyllis Harnoll and Robert Rubens with a catalogue of ballets by Phyllis Hartnoll.
      London: Macmillan & Company Limited.
    - Buckle, Richard--Nijinsky., 1971. (Box 60)
      Insert at half-title: Postcard photo of Nijinsky in L'apres Midi d'un Faune & inside back cover reviews by Walter Clemons (Newsweek 9 October 1972) & Sacheverell Sitwell (Books and Bookmen, November 71).
    - Nijinsky, Romola--Nijinsky., 1960. (Box 60)
      Middlsex: Penguin Books Limited.
      Insert after free end paper review by B.H. Haggin, (The Nation, 6 September 1952).
    - Lieven, Prince Peter--The birth of Ballet-russe., 1973. (Box 60)
      Translated by L. Zarine.
      New York: Dover Publications, Incorporated.
    - Buckle, Richard--Diaghilev., 1979. (Box 60)
      New York: Atheneum.
      Insert back cover--reviews by Arlene Croce (New Yorker, 12 May 1980), Lincoln Kirstein (New York Review of Books, 8 November 1979), David Vaughan (Los Angeles Times 4 November 1979) & Robert Kirsch (Los Angeles Times 31 October 1979).
    - Gold, Arthur, and Robert Fizdale--Misia: The life of Misia Sert., 1980. (Box 60)
      Inscribed front free end paper: For Lawrence Morton--With great admiration from Arthur Gold & Robert Fizdale. Inserted reviews by Robert Kirsch (Los Angeles Times 12 March' 80) & John Russel (New York Review of Books 6 Mar' 80).
    - Sert, Misia--Misia and the muses: The memoirs of Misia Sert., 1953. (Box 60)
      Translated by Moura Budberg, with an appreciation by Jean Cocteau.
      New York: The John Day Company.
    - Amberg, George--Ballet in America., 1954, fourth printing. (Box 60)